JOHN GUSTAVO CHOQUE CONDORI

Rebæk Søpark 5 725, 2650 Hvidovre, Denmark +45 55216983 https://www.johnchque.com johnchque@gmail.com

Entrepreneurial and driven professional. Committed to driving positive social change through initiatives related to ed-tech, mental health advocacy, open-source software, and computer ethics. Good communicator and collaborative thinker with strong logical and emotional judgment. Experience working in multicultural and multidisciplinary environments. Proven experience in leading teams.

EDUCATION

2021 - PRESENT, ERASMUS MUNDUS MASTER IN DIGITAL COMMUNICATION LEADERSHIP, UNIVERSITY OF SALZBURG - SALZBURG, AUSTRIA, AALBORG UNIVERSITY - COPENHAGEN, DENMARK

Recipient of the Erasmus Mundus scholarship from a pool of over 500 applicants. Specialisation in digital technology and management.

Thesis: "To Benefit all Humanity": Towards Fair Algorithmic Systems through Substantive Equality and Theories of Justice.

2012 - 2018, BSC COMPUTER SYSTEMS ENGINEERING, DEL VALLE UNIVERSITY - LA PAZ, BOLIVIA

Honored with the opportunity to deliver the Graduation Speech for the Class of 2018.

Thesis: System of semantic selection of personal knowledge applicable to the development of software projects.

2014 - 2015, EXCHANGE FELLOW, SOKA UNIVERSITY (創価大学) - TOKYO, JAPAN

Awarded the Makiguchi Scholarship for Foreign Students by the Makiguchi Foundation for the academic year from September 2014 to July 2015.

Exclusive selection by the Del Valle University in recognition of outstanding achievement.

WORK EXPERIENCE

JAN 2020 - JUL 2021, WEB DEVELOPER, MD SYSTEMS - EL ALTO, BOLIVIA (REMOTE)

Contributed to the development of Drupal core and modules providing bug fixes, new features, and testing. Contributed to the writing of module documentation and the development of custom modules.

JAN 2018 - APR 2019, WEB DEVELOPER, MD SYSTEMS - EL ALTO, BOLIVIA (REMOTE)

Contributed to the development of Drupal core and modules providing bug fixes, new features, and testing. Recognised for being the top 15th contributor to Drupal worldwide and received a full grant to attent to DrupalCon Nashville 2018.

Presented software development talks in Darmstadt, Germany 2018 and Davos, Switzerland 2019.

AUG 2017 - OCT 2017, DEVELOPER INTERN, ENTEL S.A. - LA PAZ, BOLIVIA

Contributed to the migration of a Joomla website to Drupal for updating the website of the company.

JAN 2016 - JAN 2017, DEVELOPER INTERN, MD SYSTEMS - ZURICH, SWITZERLAND / LA PAZ, BOLIVIA Contributed to the development of Drupal core and modules providing bug fixes, new features, and testing.

PROJECTS AND OTHER EXPERIENCE

JUL 2019 - PRESENT, CO-FOUNDER, OPENSCHOOL SOLUTIONS - VIENNA, AUSTRIA

OPENschool is an Austrian project that allows children to guide their own learning within a school classroom. Lead platform architecture definition and executed implementation utilizing Laravel Framework. Integrated automated testing procedures and developed preliminary mockups for the operational interface.

MAY 2021 - DEC 2021, CO-FOUNDER, #HISTORIASQUENOVEMOS - LA PAZ, BOLIVIA

#historiasquenovemos is a Bolivian initiative to normalise the emotional expression and recognition of the importance of men's mental health in Latin American societies.

Orchestrated logistics for gathering participant stories for the website and social media accounts. Strategically formulated and crafted social media content.

MAY 2019 - MAR 2021, CO-FOUNDER, QUANTIC GAMES - LA PAZ, BOLIVIA

Provided strategic direction for project development and lead the creation of the team's website and designed press kits.

Successfully secured acceptance into the City Hall of La Paz Incubator in 2019.

Achieved the "Best Audio" award for the game "Puma Punku" at ExpoBix 2019 for 21 000 BOB.

FEB 2020 - JUN 2020, ENVIRONMENTAL COORDINATOR, EMPODERANDO JUVENTUDES - LA PAZ, BOLIVIA

Organised team projects centered around sustainability initiatives.

Lead website development to effectively showcase project outcomes.

Organised a successful photography contest, resulting in a significant growth of Facebook followers from 800 to 2000.

MAR 2018 - AUG 2018, PRORGRAM PARTICIPANT, YOUNG SUSTAINABLE IMPACT - OSLO, NORWAY

One of the 24 individuals selected from a pool of over 8500 applicants to participate in the program.

Collaborated with diverse global participants on sustainability challenges, developing innovative solutions.

Project "Hubbing" was featured in the "To change the world" documentary (2019), produced by YSI.

Innovatiom Lab: Developed the initial idea for a "Scalable digital solution for smallhold farmers" for Yara International. Part of the winning team judged by Yara's Supply Chain EVP.

VOLUNTEERING

AGO 2022 - AGO 2023, LEADERSHIP TEAM, SUSTAINABILITY ADVOCATES - COPENHAGEN, DENMARK

Collaborated with sustainable organizations and companies to deliver interactive workshops for the team members and volunteers.

Recruited volunteers for the leadership team and project teams.

Captured high-quality photographs of workshops and events using professional equipment.

NOV 2017 - SEP 2021, LOCAL COMMITTEE LEADER, IAESTE BOLIVIA - LA PAZ, BOLIVIA

Organized events to disseminate information about the IAESTE program across multiple universities.

Provided guidance and support to foreign interns, facilitating their adaptation to the local culture.

Assisted in the successful placement of 7 students in international internships, contributing to their professional development and cross-cultural experience.

JUL 2019 - DEC 2020, PRODUCTION LEADER, TEDXUCB - LA PAZ, BOLIVIA

 $\label{lem:captured} \textbf{Captured event talks through the coordination with video and audio systems for online streaming.}$

Produced talk recordings and directed speaker presentations.

Conceptualised event venue and stage layouts.

TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

- PHP (Laravel, Drupal, Symfony, Yii)
- JavaScript (Node.js, React.js, Express.js, jQuery)
- Databases (MySQL, Firebase, Neo4j, SQL Server)
- Automated testing (Behat, PHPUnit)
- UI/UX (Gravit Designer, Figma, InkScape, CSS, Twig)
- Android (Java Native, Flutter)
- Python (Django, ACM/ICPC)
- Others (C++, C#, Git, Scrum, Jekyll, ML)
- Photo & Video (GIMP, Inkscape, Kdenlive, Darktable, Adobe Lightroom)

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Spanish (Mother tongue), English (Advanced, TOEFL IBT 108/120), Japanese (Basic)

HONOURS, AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Winner of Short Story Contest about Gender violence (June 2020), one of the ten winners among 132 participants.
- Award JCI TOYP Bolivia (Aug 2019), in the category "Personal Improvement and/or Accomplishment" one of the 10 winners during 2019 of all Bolivia.
- Speaker at FLISoL (Apr 2019, La Paz Bolivia), talk: "Sustainable development and Free Software".
- Speaker at Drupal Mountain Camp (Mar 2019, Davos Switzerland), talk: "Drupal and Android through REST: Quick integration".
- Speaker at Drupal Europe (Sep 2018, Darmstadt Germany), talk: "Drupal PKM: A personal knowledge management Drupal distro".